<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: meetup | Dennis Woo]]></title>
  <link href="http://dwoodev.github.io/categories/meetup/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://dwoodev.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-13T17:54:03-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://dwoodev.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dennis Woo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[LeanUX and Agile - Magic Workflow Sauce?]]></title>
    <link href="http://dwoodev.github.io/blog/2013/11/13/leanux-and-agile-magic-workflow-sauce/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-13T12:47:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://dwoodev.github.io/blog/2013/11/13/leanux-and-agile-magic-workflow-sauce</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Awesome presentation last night by Carbon Five&rsquo;s <a href="twitter.com/chemphill">Courtney Hemphill</a> for BayALN.</p>

<p>This preso is really magic sauce for those like me who have struggled to get design integrated into the agile development workflow.  The issue has been debated on <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/658836/how-do-you-apply-scrum-to-the-design-part-of-web-development">stackoverflow</a>.  At a recent Noisebridge training on Agile estimation, integration of design was the first question that came from the audience. A <a href="http://www.upassoc.org/upa_publications/jus/2007may/agile-ucd.pdf">whitepaper by Autodesk&rsquo;s Desiree Sy</a> suggests a staggered workflow with designers and developers on separate tracks:</p>

<p><img src="/images/custom/posts/developer-designer-different-tracks.jpg" title="Can you read this" ></p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been participant in this sort of structure in previous work and it&rsquo;s not entirely likeable.  The process of separated design was often derided as &ldquo;tossing over the fence&rdquo; &mdash; and was in practice, a mini-waterfall, the exact thing we were trying to get away from in adopting Agile.  Designers were not pairing with developers due to this structure and cultural walls went up.  Two weeks sprint cycles became de facto one month sprints, pushing risk up.</p>

<p>In ramping up on Lean Startup practices, the separate tracks approach becomes even more suspect.</p>

<p>Enter Mixing LeanUX and Agile:</p>

<iframe src="http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/26796266" width="427" height="356" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no" style="border:1px solid #CCC;border-width:1px 1px 0;margin-bottom:5px" allowfullscreen> </iframe>


<p> <div style="margin-bottom:5px"> <strong> <a href="https://www.slideshare.net/carbonfive/flowcon-mixing-lean-ux-agile-development-26796266" title="Flowcon - Mixing Lean UX &amp; Agile Development" target="_blank">Flowcon &ndash; Mixing Lean UX &amp; Agile Development</a> </strong> from <strong><a href="http://www.slideshare.net/carbonfive" target="_blank">Carbon Five</a></strong> </div></p>

<ul>
<li>They typically run 1-week sprints.</li>
<li>Smallest team is 3 — dev, designer, product manager/engagement manager.  They don’t have a dedicated scrum master, usually.</li>
<li>They do a lot of pairing and joint white-board to avoid “over the fence” issues.</li>
<li>They use a design charrette (<a href="http://www.questionablemethods.com/2011/11/design-charrette.html">http://www.questionablemethods.com/2011/11/design-charrette.html</a> — that’s the name of the blog…it’s not actually a questionable method…).</li>
<li>No traditional heavy-wireframing or picture perfect details.  Sketch it on whiteboards.</li>
<li>To enable this, they have a design AND development vocabulary ready to go.</li>
<li>They have a “balanced team” approach that includes people on the agency side and people on the client’s side.</li>
<li>They have a concept of “cadence,” which dictates:
Monday — Retrospective (must do)
Friday — CUSTOMER meeting with product, observed usage.</li>
<li>Estimation requires that they scope things down to have 1-week deliverables.</li>
<li>Typical engagement is 12 weeks, upwards to 1 year.</li>
<li>They do a sprint 0 (first week).  First customer involvement is after week 1, two weeks after kickoff, which is still pretty fast.</li>
<li>Disappearing boundaries for team members — developers design a bit; designers understand code, everybody is cross-functional.</li>
<li>They involve the customer in “hybrid prototyping” where they use cutouts of the existing product UI and have the customer help with the design.</li>
<li>They use cucumber-style BDD language to capture stories</li>
<li>They setup strong story acceptance criteria.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
